JHON ESTEBAN LUENGAS MACHADO

Mechatronics Engineer, Software Developer

@ esteban0921@gmail.com

(+57) 319 297 5121

Pogotá, Colombia

in jeluengasm

jeluengasm

PROFILE

Mechatronics Engineer and Electronics Technologist. Versatile, analytical and hardworking, qualified with skills based on responsibility, proactivity and empathy. Extensive knowledge in Backend and Frontend development, SQL, no-SQL databases and electronic design; research interests in the areas of Deep Learning, Web design, Web scraping, HW/SW development, Control Systems, SCADA systems, IIoT and Industry 4.0.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer

Infométrika S.A.S.

Mar 2021 - Jan 2022

Bogotá, Colombia

- Planning and organization through SCRUM (Taiga).
- Backend development (PHP, AdoDB, PostgreSQL, Python [Django]).
- Frontend development (JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3).
- RESTful API design (Django REST Framework).
- API testing automation (Postman).
- Code testing (Python unittest, Selenium Web Driver).
- Version control (Git, GitLab).

HW/SW developer and lecturer

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

May 2021 - Oct 2021

P Bogotá, Colombia

- Support in curve tracer design (I-V) of PV panels.
- Python programming and GUI design (OOP, PyQT).
- Lecturer in 5th and 6th Diploma in photovoltaic systems.
- Scraping (BeautifulSoup, Scrapy, urllib, JSON, XML ElementTree).
- Version control (Git, GitHub).
- Product documentation and technical support.

Student assistant

Laboratorio de Ensayos Eléctricos y Calibraciones Industriales (LABE), Universidad Nacional de Colombia

🛗 Sep 2018 - Feb 2021

P Bogotá, Colombia

- Planning (Kanban-Trello).
- SW/HW programming (C, C++, Python, Java).
- Web development with Odoo 13 (ERP and CRM, Python).
- Version control (Git, GitHub).
- Management of SQL databases (SQLite) and no-SQL databases (InfluxDB).
- Electronic design and simulation (Autodesk Eagle, LTSpice, Multisim).
- Preventive and corrective maintenance.

CERTIFICATES

- Meural Networks and Deep Learning. Coursera DeepLearning.ai.
- **Python for Everybody specialization.** Coursera University of Michigan.
- Web Application Technologies and Django. Coursera University of Michigan.
- Cre Infrastructure. Coursera Google.
- Control of Mobile Robots. Coursera Georgia Institute of technology.
- Diploma in ICT Skills: Web Accessibility and Usability Design. COLNODO.
- 🗗 Leadership program: Bogotá Líder. IDPAC & OEI.

EDUCATION

BSc. Mechatronics Engineering Universidad Nacional de Colombia

2014 - 2021

P Bogotá, Colombia

Electronics Technology

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas

2011 - 2016

P Bogotá, Colombia

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Programming

Python | Django | Flask | PHP | C | C++ | Java | SQLAlchemy | HTML5 | CSS3 | Javascript | JQuery |

Development tools

VS Code | Jupyter | Spice | Grafana

Databases

PostgreSQL MariaDB SQLite
InfluxDB MongoDB

OS

Ubuntu Desktop/Server Windows

Version control

Git Git-Flow GitHub GitLab

• Production/Planning

Kanban/Trello SCRUM/Taiga

MS Office/LibreOffice ETEX

Languages

Spanish | English

VOLUNTEERING

- C Academic tutor, Project manager. Fundación Aspirantes.org.
- Leader, academic tutor. Universidad Nacional de Colombia.
- Leader, academic tutor. Universidad Nacional de Colombia.

STRENGTHS

Decision Making Motivator & Leader

Conflict Resolution Time Management

Self-taught Flexibility and Adaptability